Waseem Mohammad Rochdale, United Kingdom

Email: wmohammad83@icloud.com

Portfolio Page: https://wmohammad83.github.io/Bootstrap-Portfolio/LinkedIn: http://linkedin.com/in/waseem-mohammad-a587061b2

Github: https://github.com/wmohammad83

Personal Profile

A highly motivated and enthusiastic individual with a strong passion for technology, with almost 2 decades worth of customer service experience from different sectors. Moving across to the technology field, I have quickly learned a range of technical skills from managing users in active directory to troubleshooting physical networks.

I have developed a keen interest in web development where I have learned how to make simple websites using HTML, CSS and wish to take this further into a full-time career. I have enrolled onto a frontend web development bootcamp by Trillogy where I am learning additional skills to build on my current knowledge including Bootstrap, JavaScript, NodeJS and React and will receive a certificate on completion.

Education and Training

Nov 22 – March 23	Trilogy Frontend Web Development Bootcamp Certificate Covering all aspects of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React	
Jan 2021	Jamf 100	PASS
July 2020	CCNA 200-301	PASS
March 2020	ITIL Foundation Course	PASS
Oct 2016	Just IT Training Ltd, London	
	Network Professional Program	
	CompTIA 220-901	PASS
	CompTIA 220-902	PASS
	Windows 10 70-698	PASS
July 2007	ABDO Final Practical Exam	PASS
July 2005	ABDO Practical Exam	PASS
2002-2006	Anglia Ruskin University (Cambridge)	
	Ophthalmic Dispensing with Chemistry BSc	
2000-2002	Hopwood Hall College (Middleton)	
	AVCE Science	D, D
	AS level World Development	D
	Level 2 Communication	Pass
	Level 2 Information Technology	Pass
1999	Matthew Moss High School	
	3 GCSEs including mathematics and science	A-C

Projects

ToWatchIt

GitHub: https://github.com/thomasptharakan/ToWatchlt https://thomasptharakan.github.io/ToWatchlt/

- The main functionality of our application is adding the desired movies to your movie list and watch them in your free time. The app will run in the browser where the HTML and CSS is dynamically created using JavaScript.
- Thomas Tharakan, Waseem Mohammad, Victor Iglunov, Tina Georgescu
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

Weather Dashboard

GitHub: https://github.com/wmohammad83/weather-dashboard/
URL: https://wmohammad83.github.io/weather-dashboard/

- The aim of this project was to create an application where a user could search for the weather in a particular location. The data it retrieves comes from the open weather api and display it in the browser.
- Waseem
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, NodeJS

ReadMe Generator

GitHub: https://github.com/wmohammad83/ReadMeGenerator

- This application can be used to generate a readme.md file after it has taken some input from the user through the console. It uses inquirer and fs to retrieve the data and create the file.
- Waseem
- JavaScript, NodeJS, npm

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Git & GitHub
- NodeJS
- React

Employment History

Sep 2021 - Present

ICT Cluster Manager Oasis Community Learning

- Responsible for the smooth running of 4 academies making sure that the technicians are onsite and completing service tickets in a timely manner within SLAs
- · Working closely with project managers and senior managers to complete project work
- Working with technologies such as Meraki, Jamf Pro and paper cut to aid users with issues
- Imaging desktops and laptops using WDS and SCCM to install applications such as Office 365

- Assisting with desk moves and patching in the relevant network ports in the server cabinet
- Providing great customer service ensuring that services we provide is of good standard

July 2019 – Oct 2021 IT Technician Oasis Community Learning

- Supporting teaching staff and students with day to day IT activities (desktop support/printing)
- Supporting users within a Microsoft/Apple environment
- Imaging and configuring desktop and laptop devices for use within the academies using WDS and SCCM
- Assisting staff/students with Apple iPad devices managed by Jamf
- Desktop moves and network patching
- Various project work including an academy move and setup, Project Horizon
- During coved-19 pandemic I worked on 1st line to support students, parents and teachers for online learning

08/18 – 07/19 Field Engineer Daisy IT Services Ltd

- Attend sites around the North West to resolve various IT/epos system issues within the SLA
- Problem solving of networks, desktop pcs, peripherals
- Re-imaging desktops using supplied images for sites
- Contacting 3rd parties to give updates and to complete builds
- Communicating with the customer to explain the best solution in a language the customer understands
- Give excellent customer service

07/15 - Present	Locum Dispensing Optician Specsavers, Asda, Independent Opticians
02/11 - 07/15	Dispensing Optician Specsavers, Rochdale
11/10 - 02/11	Locum Dispensing Optician Asda, Tesco, Independent Opticians
06/10 - 10/10	Dispensing Optician Specsavers, Bolton
08/07 - 05/10	Dispensing Optician D&A Opticians, Manchester Arndale Centre
08/06 - 08/07	Pre-Reg Dispensing Optician

Specsavers, Morley

Hobbies: Occasional console gaming (Xbox), keeping fit and healthy, learning about new technologies particularly networking. I am also into home automation where I have setup Apple HomeKit to control lights, heating using sensors available on the market.

Additional information: I have a full driving licence and own a car References available upon request